# Sebastián Pereira Rivero

# Software Developer

Ciudad de la Costa, Uruguay +598 98 900 649 spereirarivero93@gmail.com LinkedIn

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Jr/Mid Software Engineer - Occupier

OCT 2021 - AUG 2023

- Contributed maintaining the codebase of a Lease Accounting Platform with 5k users per day, and 200+ customers operating all over the USA.
- Built several product features and UX/UI improvements, some of them direct customer requests that helped to improve client retention statistics and close new deals.
- Implemented migration from REST to GraphQL of various Models, that helped to improve performance and reduce development time.

## **SSr RPA Developer** - BASF Services America

JAN 2020 - AUG 2020

- Implemented complex process automation with high impact for several internal clients, helping to reduce 500+ hours of manual processing.
- Implemented a Bot that runs with parallel instances in charge of Monthly Closing for 50+ accounts, it integrates to SAP(ERP) and in communication with internal APIs and services, reducing a week of manual work to just a couple hours.
- Formed part of an international RPA Engineers team based in Germany with continuous code and performance reviews.

# **RPA Developer** - Intermedia

NOV 2018 - DEC 2019

- Worked on analysis, implementation and deployment of 30+ automation bots for different user's business and accounting manual processes.
- Formed part of a company Agility restructure, attending a Scrum course and having a crucial role to use new learned practices on a daily basis.
- Helped a client to reduce 500+ hours of user's manual and repetitive tasks, gaining the client's employees valuable time.

## Script Developer - Asignet

SEP 2016 - NOV 2018

- Contribute implementing a system for invoice data processing.
- Build 100+ scripts that download 1000+ invoices per month.
- Created 40+ of parser models that processed and persisted several Invoice's relevant values in a database.

#### **EDUCATION**

### Programer Analyst - Universidad ORT Uruguay MAR 2018 - DEC 2020

A short career with a very high practical level. Learned concepts of the full software development cycle, and the process of analyzing, thinking out of the box and working with good practices and maintainable software.

### IT High School (Bachillerato) - ESI Buceo (UTU) MAR 2010 - DEC 2014

First introduction to various areas of computer science like electronics, networking, infrastructure, web design, Linux bash script, and Object Oriented Programming using Java.

#### **PROFILE**

I am a Software Developer with seven years of experience, having great skills like excellent reasoning ability, critical thinking, and a problem-solving mindset that help me build and contribute to building excellent products.

During the last years I enrolled myself in several internet courses and bootcamps to learn and gain expertise in popular web development tech stacks that lead me to join an excellent company to collaborate effectively with their mission and objectives.

I'm in constant pursuit of new challenges to fuel my passion for continuous learning and professional growth.

Looking forward to joining rich culture companies where teamwork, agile mindset and attention to detail are present on a daily basis.

#### **TECHNICAL EXPERTISE**

I feel confident and have good experience with: JavaScript, React, Redux, Git, Node, Express and MySQL

Have some experience and want to keep learning:
TypeScript, NextJS, Jest, React
Native, GraphQL, NestJS,
Postgres, CI/CD, among others.

Also have decent to little experience with: Ruby on Rails, Python, C#, Java, Visual Basic, UiPath, etc.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish - Native English - C1 Advanced Portuguese - A2 Basic